what's up everybody it's Jake back in
the barbin garage gym and for today's
review I've got the big board that is
the force USA X20 it's a power rack it's
a cable machine it can cook you dinner
I'm just kidding they can't do that but
it can do a lot of things and I'm pretty
pumped to walk you through everything it
has to offer from the price and the
features as well as some pros and cons
but most importantly who should or maybe
should not add this to their home gym
before I get going with all that though
you know we've reviewed a lot of power
racks squat racks and even cable
machines all over on barbin.com so if
you want to browse our best list for any
of those categories just search barbin
best power rack squat rack or cable
machine you can find out for yourself
which ones that we like the best
foreign
[Music]
let's talk about the cables first and
foremost I love using a cable machine
when I'm at the gym so the fact that
there's technically one built in right
here with this rack is really nice the
stacks on either side reach up to 289
pounds and they operate on a two to one
ratio so two to one ratio cables it's
going to require half of the actual
force needed to move their weight
resistance so let's say you have 80
pounds loaded up it's only going to
require about 40 pounds of force to
actually move that weight in a two to
one cable actually can move further away
from the rack so you can walk further
away and do your exercises the Chrome
uprights are made of 11 gauge steel and
this thing is rated to hold up to 990
pounds which is a lot of weight to say
the least so there's a lot of people
that can use this power rack right here
and it essentially is a power rack so
there's a ton of room for you to work
with in the actual rack it also comes
with some half safety arms so you can
work out outside of the wrap if you
choose to do so it features West Side
spacing with one inch diameter holes and
the 42 different adjustment points that
are available to you it has a built-in
pull-up bar it comes with a low row foot
plate as well as a landmine attachment
you have eight storage horns you know
four on either side of the rack you have
two barbell storage holders and you can
even add on an accessories package
that's going to include 12 more
attachments for you to work out with
including a TV mount yeah that's right
you heard me a TV mount because who
doesn't want to watch their favorite
show while they're getting a lift in
thank you
[Music]
okay now that I've had a chance to catch
my breath let's talk about a couple cons
you might experience with the X20 now I
know there's a pretty common phrase you
know about assuming but I think it's
pretty safe to assume that this is an
expensive piece of equipment and you're
right it is so the base package is
listed right around 5500 but once you
tack on shipping if you want to get the
white glove assembly and if you want to
add on the accessories package you're
gonna be spending over seven thousand
dollars on this piece of equipment and
yeah it has pretty much everything you
could ask for it could be the only piece
of equipment you really need in your
home gym but that's a lot of money to be
spending the white glove assembly is
extra like I just said but it's kind of
crucial because this is going to take
you around five or six hours to put
together that's a really long time
that's how long it took a professional
to do it so think about how long it
would take you at home to do it by
yourself and lastly this thing is pretty
massive right so it's right around seven
and a half feet tall and and we only had
about an inch of clearance here in the
garage and it's about six feet wide as
well so finding just The Sweet Spot for
it to go in your home gym is going to be
a problem itself
[Music]
okay so let's break down pricing a
little bit more now once again the base
package with the X20 is listed right
around fifty five hundred dollars
shipping is about 400 bucks upgrade kits
around eight hundred dollars and so the
white glove assembly is kind of going to
be determined based off of if you want
the upgrade kit or not so you're either
going to be spending around 650 or 750
bucks add all that together and what do
you have you're gonna be spending around
7 500 on this piece of equipment okay
now 7 500 that's a ton of money and it's
you know safe to assume once again that
this is one of the most expensive
options that are available online so you
want to save a couple thousand dollars
maybe yeah there's some other options
for you to choose from Force USA
actually has a couple you know
themselves that they offer that you
could choose from as well but you know
if you can afford it I think that this
will be worth the money it can be the
true centerpiece of your home gym and
you really won't need any other
equipment maybe other than some
dumbbells or a kettlebell or two
[Music]
okay so in terms of the build of the X20
you know once again these Chrome
uprights are made from 11 gauge steel
that's professional quality it's rated
to hold up to 990 pounds which is a very
very high number now yeah it is coated
in chrome chrome is obviously prone to
some Rust and corrosion we have a tiny
bit built up but that's also because
ours was sitting in a storage unit for
quite a while so that could have you
know definitely played a factor into it
now you can clean that up a little bit
and remove some of that just be careful
don't use anything too harsh or else you
know you might ruin the Chrome and you
definitely don't want that now it's
about seven and a half feet tall outside
of the rack is almost six feet wide and
from front to back of the actual rack
it's about seven feet in length or so
now inside the actual rack it's just
under three and a half feet wide and
from front to back it's about six feet
in length or so so there's a lot of room
for you to work within the rack itself
which is really nice the uprights also
feature West Side spacing so each
adjustment point the hole is one inch in
diameter so the upper portion of the
upright each hole is going to be three
inches apart from one another while the
lower portion is right at one and a half
inches apart
[Music]
okay so let's talk about the accessories
a little bit now with the X20 and if you
can't tell by now there's a lot for you
to work out with now I could sit here
and name off all 18 of them for you guys
that might be a little bit boring so why
don't I just focus on my favorite
attachments that I like to use so first
and foremost I really love this low row
foot plate I think it's pretty unique
you know it's going to allow me to do my
rows you know without doing anything too
extra to you know be able to do that
also really love the lat pull down seat
that comes you know with that upgraded
package it's going to allow me to really
focus on my lat pull-downs and that's
pretty cool too it just attaches right
up here to the front of the rack it's
pretty easy to do it I also really like
the addition of the Jammer arms that's
pretty unique you know you don't really
see that in all equipment out there
right now and that's just pretty cool
you know it's going to add in some extra
workouts for you to do I really like the
multi-grip pull-up bar on the top right
here you know I like the different
angles you can use but also really enjoy
the knurled handles now I don't know the
diameter of the handles but compared to
some dumbbells
it's around 34 millimeters or so just
kind of how it feels in my hands also
you know really love the knurled handles
that you can use for the cable machine
it's going to give you a really solid
grip as you're doing some chest flies or
even some lateral raises too
all right y'all it's the moment you
waited for a full walk around now with
the X20 it's gonna take a minute so bear
with me but let's get to it all right so
in the back right here I don't have any
weights on here at the moment so I
wanted you to be able to see you know
where this barbell storage holder is
it's really nice you know if you're
somebody who has multiple barbells you
know storage is made really easy with
that right here you have four different
weight horns for you to work with on
either side I think it's really cool how
you can actually adjust these to you
know find The Sweet Spot you know for
all your plates to fit on each horn now
I've got this dip handle attachment
right here
this is really nice I'm going to show
you how to you know securely put it in
the front of your rack so you can work
out with it so basically you're just
going to take this guy right here place
it in one of the holes wherever whatever
height you want it's really not that
much to it
slide it in there
twist it and there's this little handle
right here you pull out
and that's going to lock in for you and
as you can see it's not going anywhere
and you can sit here and do dips
all day long
in these 11 gauge steel uprights you
know they're going to be able to hold
your body weight and when you take it
out it's the same process in reverse
order so you'll pull out on this pin
twist
and then pull this guy right out easy
done set this aside really fast
all right now same goes for your lat
pull down seat attachment it's literally
the exact same process but you know just
for the sake of the video I'm going to
show you again so you slide this guy in
just like that
you're gonna twist pull out on that PIN
lock it in and if you know I had this
low enough for me to actually sit you
know you could sit down right here and
pull down you know with your pull down
attachment so that's really cool let me
go ahead and pull this out of the way
too so it's not getting in my way
all right
now your landmine attachment can go on
either side of the feet right here it's
really easy to do
go ahead and take this out really fast
what you do is you just attach this
piece right here to the front and then
you just slide the end right here
all the way through
and it's not going to come out on you on
your own there's a little washer right
here you have to line up again and
that'll make it come out so that's
really cool you can throw your barbell
in there you can add on that t-bar
attachment I'm going to show you in a
second do t-bar rows a bunch of stuff
it's really cool now once again these
Chrome safety arms are West Side spacing
so each hole is one inch in diameter and
as you go up they're further spaced
apart so up here the three inches apart
while on the bottom they're one and a
half inches apart now
the Engravings there's really actually
not engraved at all but you do have
markings right here so you can always
see you know which spacing you're going
to work with which is pretty cool now
obviously you do have cables on each
side I'm going to show you how to adjust
them it's really easy you have a pin on
either side you just pull out and you
have a knurled handle right here and
you're able to slide down or take it
right back up
it's really easy to do so and you know
it's pretty simple when it comes to
switching out your attachments you know
it's just a normal clip right here you
just
slide it on out and you can switch it
for whatever you want to do
now I really like these handles right
here that are part of the accessories
package the knurling's not you know
something you'll find on a barbell for
example but you know it's a pretty nice
grip right there you're able to get you
know some solid grip while you're
working out and these rotate a little
bit which could come in handy when
you're doing some bicep curls you know
whatever I really like that I also
really like this low row foot plate
right here it's really cool to me you
know all you have to do is lower your
cable all the way down attach your bar
and then you can sit here and do rows I
just really like that you know I think
that that's pretty cool and to you know
attach this to the foot of the actual
rack is the same process as you would do
with the landmine attachment so you have
a pin right here it's it's literally
everything is the exact same process
which is really cool all right now if we
come into the rack you'll see this is
where your safety arms are going to be
now you can adjust these to whatever
height you want whenever necessary it's
pretty easy to do so all you got to do
is Twist
push away or slide away from the rack
and it's going to come right out and you
can select you know whatever height is
necessary for you
sometimes it can be a little tricky to
make everything line up and then you
just twist it back down and it's it's
nice and secure it's not gonna you know
just slide out I like how it is lined
with plastic right here so it's going to
protect your barbell a little bit if you
were to drop it for whatever reason it's
a nice little safety touch right there I
also like how these J Hooks are also
lined with plastic you know
a lot of times
barbell holders you know j-hooks they
don't have that so that's going to be
really good for your barbell it's going
to prevent it from you know getting
damaged over time all right now let's
transition further back into the rack
now let's highlight this stack right
here of Weights once again this goes up
to 289 pounds and these cables operate
on a two to one ratio so say you have 80
pounds you know load it up it's really
only going to require 40 pounds of force
for you to move it but there's still a
lot of weight right here for you to work
out with now both sides right here you
know these panelings have exercise
guides which is going to be really
helpful for some people you know you
don't necessarily know what to do with a
cable machine well Force USA has you
covered right here now
the storage shelves are really nice in
my opinion you could throw some
dumbbells on here if you want to but I
just kind of like having all of my
accessories separated I really really
like this multi-grip pull down bar right
here you have different angles you can
work with and that's just really nice
every single handle right here is
knurled so you're going to get a pretty
good grip while you're working out let
me put this guy back really fast
now this is the ankle cuff that comes
with it
it's lined right here it's pretty soft
on the inside it's going to allow you to
do some glute Kickbacks and work on your
adductors and abductors as well if you
want to do so these are the plastic
handles that come with that basic
package these are okay I mean it's got a
little bit of a grip right here but I
gotta say I like the knurled handles
better for obvious reasons now it does
come with a pair of clamps right here
for your barbell for when you're working
out which is really nice if you don't
have any it's going to be a really nice
touch right there and this is a little
short bar attachment that you have you
can use this for your low row foot plate
it's going to be a nice width right
there for your grip you have Tony
there's a lot right here to work out
with
this is that little angled bar right
here if you do some tricep push Downs
with you know it's going to really
Target your tricep pedals right there
not to hit my head on this barbell you
also have this other pull down bar which
is really nice you know you can work
this on a focus on a regular grip as
well as a wide grip if you want to do so
and then you also have this other
attachment right here which is really
nice and then this is that t-bar
attachment down here so I'll explain in
a second but really what's going to
happen is your barbell is going to go in
here you screw this in and it's going to
be you know secured nice and tightly
through your barbell just be careful
though because you know that is metal on
metal and it might cause a little bit of
damage to your loading sleeve if you're
not super careful but I really like this
because it's going to allow you to do
some t-bar rows without actually having
you know a t-bar machine I guess you
could say without that chest support so
that's really cool I really like this
right here I also really like these
Jammer arms this is pretty unique in my
opinion you know not every single power
rack out there has this for you to work
out with so it's a pretty easy process
to assemble it you know just go ahead
and set these in here
and then you want to screw in this
little end right here and be careful
when you take it apart this is um
definitely made of steel and it tends to
just want to fall as soon as it is all
the way loosened enough it's felt
falling on my foot a couple times and
trust me that hurt you don't you don't
want that happen to you so basically
just go ahead and screw this back in if
I get the threads to align
there we go
screw it in nice and tight
and you could raise this up higher than
I have it right now you're going to want
to but this is basically how you do it
and you can just walk up and put your
hand right here it's going to allow you
to do a lot of exercises where you can
just pull this up it's going to be great
for you know your upper chest and this
whole area right here so that's really
nice it's a pretty cool workout I gotta
say one thing I definitely can't forget
to mention is this multi-group pull-up
bar now I opted out of that regular
pull-up bar without the knurl any type
of knurling on it I prefer to have
knurling I prefer to have a good grip
and I'm sure you will too so this is
really nice you know you can do some
wide grip pull-ups you can do some
different angles you can do your close
grip and it's just you know
this thing's really sturdy you know it's
not going to topple over on you if you
want though I forgot to mention you can
bolt this into the ground there's spots
for it on both of the feet in the front
and in the back you could bolt this down
but it weighs around two tons so I
really don't think you're gonna need to
do that another cool thing though with
this multi-grip pull-up bar
so you can actually attach a punching
bag right here if you want to do so and
that's really cool as well well as some
TRX bands as well that's kind of cool
now let's walk around back right here I
want to show you these half safety arms
as you can see you know they're
definitely smaller than the ones that
are on the inside and this is pretty
cool you know if you want to do some
squats in front of the rack you
definitely can it's the same process as
everything else you just slide this guy
in right here
give it a twist
and this is really cool you know it's
lined with plastic as well and you can
definitely do some squats in front of
the rack and that's just pretty cool all
right now let's go around to the side
one more time I got a couple more things
to show you here you know on the back
right here you do have it they are going
to include some butterfly clamps it's
gonna be really nice you know just for
added safety feature you know you throw
your weight plates on here you slide one
of these bad boys on and your plates
aren't going to fall off so that's just
for safety that's a nice little touch
this is also the aluminum bar that's
going to come with your original
purchase this is pretty cool because it
can attach to both of the cables and
it's basically going to feel like a
Smith machine with this power rack and
that's just pretty cool it's a nice
little you know safety workout as well
and I have to mention I cannot forget to
mention the band pegs right here at the
bottom
set this guy to the side without it
falling on me basically this is really
cool it's going to allow you to get more
resistance as you're going to do a bench
press even if you're squatting
let me make sure this doesn't move on me
so basically you know you just go like
this throw your resistance band on there
and that's going to add you know
obviously more resistance to your
workouts now obviously there's a lot for
you to do with this power rack 18
different attachments you know hundreds
of exercises for you to do it weighs
around two tons like I said it's not
gonna move it's got 11 gauge steel
uprights it's going to be in it for the
long haul and remember we had a
professional come out and put this
together and it took him around five and
a half hours so I would suggest that too
because if not you're looking at
probably a full day maybe even a two day
project
foreign
USA X20 well honestly this might be more
tailored to people who have a large
budget and you know a lot of available
space to house this Behemoth of a
product but if you have both of those
things I think you're gonna be really
happy because you can do just about
anything you want with just this rack
and because of that versatility you know
this rack can really be the centerpiece
of your gym and trust me it's going to
be the centerpiece because once again
it's huge and if you're looking for a
rack that you know is in fact Built For
the Long Haul I think you're going to
love the fact these uprights are made
from 11 gauge steel
now when it comes to those who might not
want to purchase the X20 it really just
boils down to two factors money and you
know available space so if you don't
want to spend anywhere from 65 up to 7
500 on one piece of equipment you know
I'd suggest looking at some other
options because there's some other
options out there that are a couple
Grand cheaper they it just might not
feature you know 11 gauge steel and be
rated to hold up to as much weight as
this one can and also if you don't have
enough space for this rack then you
definitely don't need to buy I mean we
almost weren't able to house it in our
garage because of the height we only
have one inch of clearance so you
definitely want to be sure to factor in
that and really measure everything out
or else this simply just won't fit and
you'll have wasted your money
[Music]
well that's a wrap on today's review
over the force USA X20 I personally love
this thing I felt like a little kid on
Christmas morning the day I finally got
it all set up and was able to work out
with it I can do almost anything that I
want with this rack you know because of
the multiple attachments that it comes
with and that you can add on remember
though it is one of the more expensive
options on the market and it's massive
so you have to make sure that it's going
to fit in your available space before
you buy it thanks for watching everybody
I hope this video was really helpful
that I was able to really break down
everything that the force USA X20 has to
offer as always you know stay posted for
my next review but for now head over to
barbin.com and you can read more about
this bad boy right here just search bar
Bend Force USA X20 Pro review and you'll
find all the details that we discussed
here today now I'm gonna go get a
workout in I'll catch y'all later
foreign